Guide to the University Task Force on Child Care records, 1985-1990
Duke University. University Archives
University Task Force on Child Care records 1985-1990
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. University Task Force on Child Care.
3.0 linear feet Extent: 2,000 Items
The University Task Force on Child Care was appointed by President Keith Brodie in 1988 and chaired by Dr. Paula Burger, Vice Provost for Academic Services. It was dissolved in 1990. The collection includes minutes, correspondence, reports, audiocassettes, and printed material documenting the creation and organization of the task force and its study of child care issues at Duke University. It ranges in date from 1985-1990.
uatfcc
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The University Task Force on Child Care records, were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1994.
Historical Note
The University Task Force on Child Care was appointed by President Keith Brodie in 1988 and chaired by Dr. Paula Burger, Vice Provost for Academic Services. Its charge included the consideration of issues regarding child care and the establishment of a child care facility for Duke University faculty, staff, and students. The task force was dissolved by Dr. Brodie in 1990. Later that year, he created the University Committee for Family and Child Care Issues.
Collection Overview
The collection includes minutes, correspondence, reports, audiocassettes, and printed material documenting the creation and organization of the task force and its study of child care issues at Duke University. Reflected in the records are the task force's consideration of various child care alternatives, the gathering of data and opinions from the University community, cost analyses, and its recommendations to the officers of the University. The establishment of the Children's Campus, Duke University's child care facility is documented in the records.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century.; Duke University. University Task Force on Child Care.; Duke University. Children's Campus, Inc.; Children -- Services for.
Related Material
President H. Keith H. Brodie records, 1963-1994.
Duke University Archives.
University Committee for Family and Child Care Issues records,
Duke University Archives.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Accreditation, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi Omega, 1989-1990
  - Child Care Coordinator, 1989
  - Child Care Center Policies
  - Child Care Facility, Finances, 1987-1990
  - Child Care Survey, 1989
  - Child Care Survey and Child Care Models, 1986-1989
  - Children's Campus, Inc., Bylaws, 1990
  - Children's Campus, Inc., Construction, 1990
  - Children's Campus, Inc., Opening, 1990
  - Children's Campus, Inc., Support Services Meeting, 1990
  - Coalition/Lobbying, 1989-1990
  - Consultants, Ziegler; Annab (Tapes), circa 1989
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990
  - Correspondence, Employee Letters, 1989-1990
  - Elderly/Child Care Project, 1989
  - Facilities Committee, 1989-1990
  - Flexible Benefits, 1989-1990
  - Fund Raising Subcommittee, 1989-1990
  - Graduate Students, Child Care Issues, 1990
  - Insurance, 1989
  - Licensing, 1989-1990
  - Licensing and City Zoning Requirements, 1988
  - Management Firms/Consultants, 1988-1989
  - Minutes, 1988-1990
  - Presentations/Feedback, 1988-1990
  - Projected Costs, 1989-1990
  - Public Relations, 1989-1990
  - Reports, Recommendations and Proposals, 1985-1989
  - Recommendations to Dr. Brodie, 1989-1991
  - Responses to the Child Care Newsletter, 1989
  - Senior Class Gift, 1989-1990
  - Subcommittee on the Child Care Initiatives, 1989-1990
  - Task Force: Goals and Objectives, 1989
  - Task Force: Organization and Structure, 1988-1990
  - Transitional Center, 1989
  - Clippings, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
  - Printed Material, 1985-1990
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1989
  - Legal and Business Aspects of Starting and Operating a Child Care Center, 1988
  - Child Care Options: Decision Making Guide, 1989